Tnsae Nebyou Asefa

Disciplined and Energetic

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

tnsaeasefa08@gmail.com

+251 90 610 9232

As a backend developer, have more than 3 years of proven experience being comfortable working with Python, the Django framework, and SQL for building web-based applications and systems. Understanding and working according to the company's interests and coding scalable programs are my biggest strengths. And, while being a great problem solver and good team-mate, who is eager to learn new things in life.

Work Experience

Junior Backend Developer (Intern)

Anku ICT-solution - Addis Ababa April 2021 to July 2021

Contributed on a Project

Website for the Ethiopian Tech-innovation minister

Previously, Events were held on paper-based notice or were posted on a wall. This web development took more than half a year and using Python and specifically Django to work on this task, the project has made it easy to control anybody who tried to cheat attendance, made it cheap to organize the event, and played some value in contributing to the cleanness of the environment. 1. Authorized individuals can create an Event

- 2. Registers speakers of the event.
- 3. Stores data in SQL database
- 4. Event participants can register on to Events.
- 5. Admin can see who registered.
- 6. Checks if someone was present at the event.
- 7. Email similar events to attend for previous attendees.
- 8. Summaries about events were posted on their own blog after the event
- 9. Anonymous comments can be given by those who attended up votes and down votes were given to events after the event, anonymously. and so on

Backend Developer (contractual)

Adwa Tech - Remote

November 2021 to March 2022

Contributed on a Project

Agricultural Prediction System for Sidama, Ethiopia Region

In this location, Farmers farm with a traditional form of agriculture, and have some useful knowledge and by adding it with some data-driven decisions, the team thought about solving water scarcity during droughts, by preparing for plant diseases, prices and the demand levels for some period. This Django based backend project was built entirely in python. The Django backend and the Prediction system were connected using pickle also used an agile software development pattern and divided the project into micro-services.

- The system can make predictions based on previously recorded data.
- Data collectors were able to collect data from farmers on their phones, easily.
- Data collected were able to be classified by whom, where, and when they were collected.
- Display the outcome of the data analysis on the front end• Display the prediction results on the front end for the admin
- The system stores data in an SQL database.
- · An authorized user can download data as a spreadsheet and upload a spreadsheet to the database for future use.
- Data Analysis Python Django SQL Micro-services Agile Software Development and so on

Backend Developer (Contractual)

Alfac IT-solution - Remote August 2021 to October 2021

A web based house and rental price prediction

This project was assigned to the company by the city for a website to control the price of housing. After the global pandemic Inflation has hit most of the world and due to the increase in population in cities. It is understandable that housing is not affordable anymore. This project is to solve this by taking pre-measures for what is to come, using python frameworks to understand the pattern of the data and show the responsible body what is going to come.

- Enter data about their salary and where they live based on their consent.
- The system can store recorded data in SQL
- The system can take an input and give an output of data in CSV format to an authorized user.
- the system does data analysis for the given input
- The system makes a prediction of the rental prices in 2 years timeframe based on different locations.

Education

B.Sc in Computer Engineering

Mekelle University - Tigray September 2016 to April 2022

Skills

- Python (4 years)
- Django (3 years)
- Flask (1 year)
- Data analytics (1 year)
- · Docker (1 year)
- SQL (3 years)
- HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Jinja2